<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Violetta van Veen</title>
    <link>https://violettavanveen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Violetta van Veen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://violettavanveen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://violettavanveen.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://violettavanveen.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a master&amp;rsquo;s student in Public Policy and Development at Paris School of Economics. I graduated summa cum laude in July 2021 with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in Economics, Markets and Institutions at the University of Bologna, where I was a fellow at Collegio Superiore.
My research interests lie primarily in the field of labor economics, in general as well as in particular from a gender perspective. This is a field I have been interested in since taking a course in Labor Economics during my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s as additional coursework beyond the requirements for my degree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://violettavanveen.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://violettavanveen.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Academic Projects  Replication study of Hatton (2016)  Project for the Econometrics course at Tilburg University PDF   Gender-based division of labor and fertility: from Becker (1960)&amp;rsquo;s theory to recent debates  Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s final project PDF, Italian   Gender equality in Italian honors colleges  Paper for the Gender Equality and Social Inclusion at Collegio Superiore PDF, Italian   On the Perception of Taxes  Paper for the Public Economics course at University of Bologna PDF, Italian    Articles  The evolution of the internet between platform and infrastructure  Published online by Istituto Treccani (first part, second part, Italian)    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
