<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Violetta van Veen</title>
    <link>https://violettavanveen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Violetta van Veen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://violettavanveen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://violettavanveen.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://violettavanveen.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Pre-Doctoral Research Assistant at the International Inequalities Institute at the London School of Economics, working with Arun Advani and Andy Summers.
I graduated summa cum laude with a master&amp;rsquo;s in Economics from the Paris School of Economics in September 2023. Prior to that, I graduated summa cum laude in July 2021 with a bachelor’s in Economics from the University of Bologna, where I was a fellow at Collegio Superiore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://violettavanveen.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://violettavanveen.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Publications  The Genesis and Evolution of the Blue Banana Region (History of Economic Thought and Policy, 2022, with L. Capoani, G. Bortoletto, S. Fratini, and C. Imbesi)  This article aims to present a balanced bibliographic review on the genesis of the Blue Banana and its further developments. Different contributions have been collected to obtain a comprehensive picture of the European regional concept from both historical and theoretical perspectives. Besides the review of the litera-ture, this article contributes to the existing research on the Blue Banana with a comprehensive investigation of its current features, including urbanization, infra-structures, labor market, productivity, and competitiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
